So, in this lecture, I'm going to take a look at what is governance and compliance
mean, and what are some of the common industry regulations that AWS adhere to.
So, what is governance?
Governance is a framework that guides how end users make use of cloud services by defining
and creating policies to control cost, minimize security risk, improve efficiency,
and then accelerate deployment.
So, in summary, it's a framework which helps you in these four aspects.
Now, let's try and understand what is compliance.
Compliance in AWS refers to adhering to various industry specific and general data protection,
regulations and standards.
So, standards could refer to industry specific regulations such as HIPAA for health care,
PCIDSS for payment security, then there could be general data protection regulations
like the GDPR, CCPA, and then there could be other compliance programs such as SOC and FEDRA.
So, these are some of the general governance and compliance regulations across the industry.
Now, let's take a look at some of the specific regulatory compliance standards for AI systems.
So, the first one and recently launched is the AI Act European Union, EU AI Act.
The AI Act is the first ever legal framework on AI which addresses the risks of AI and if
it is go to this link and it defines four different levels of risk.
So, you have the unacceptable risk, high risk, limited risk and minimal risk.
So, if you see the high risk AI systems identified as high risk including AI technology
used in critical infrastructure such as transport, educational or vocational training may
determine the access to education and professional courses of someone else's life.
So, scoring of exams.
So, these are some of the areas that it defines as high risk and then we have the limited
risk.
So, let's say you are creating a chatbot.
So, humans should be made aware that they are interacting with a machine so that they
can take an informed decision or continue to step back and then you have minimal or
no risk.
So, examples of these are AI enabled video game or Gmail spam filters.
Now, what this regulation says is that if you are in the high risk category then these
are the steps you need to follow.
A high risk AI system is developed then in the second step it needs to undergo the conformity
assessment and comply with AI requirements then it needs to register in the EU database.
Then finally it needs to make a declaration of conformity needs to be signed and then it
can go ahead and place it in the market and if there are any substantial changes then it
needs to go through this life cycle again.
The second one is algorithmic accountability act of 2023 and this act requires companies
to assess the impact of AI systems and use it and sell.
So, if I just go to this link so this law is applicable in US the algorithmic accountability
act of 2023 requires companies to assess the impact of AI systems, the use and sell creates
new transparency about when and how such systems are used.
So, you can go through this link in the PowerPoint and read a little more about it.
And the third one is the GDPR Act so it applies to the processing of personal data within
EU and provides specific data protection guidelines for transparency liability ethic bias
and risk and we already discussed some of these aspects in the responsible AI section.
Okay, now let's talk a little bit about few more standards.
One is the international organization for standardization or ISO so it specifically has ISO
IEC 4201 2023 which focuses on the AI systems so I will not go into the details of this
AI standards if you are interested you can just go through this link and read a little
bit more about it.
And then finally we have the systems and organization control or SOC which focuses on
three areas for SOC 1 for financial reporting SOC 2 for design and operational effectiveness
of internal controls and then SOC 3 for presenting SOC 2 reports information to general
public.
So if we can just go to this link so you can see here AWS system and organization control
SOC reports are independent third party examination reports that demonstrate how AWS
achieves key compliance, control and objectives.
So you can read about AWS SOC report on AWS artifacts and then AWS SOC 2 on security
availability, confidentiality and privacy reports on AWS artifacts and then finally
for SOC 3 you can read this publicly available web paper.
Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture I'll see in the next lecture.
Thank you.